# Nicolas Capelier

+33 6 52 33 23 85 capelier.nicolas@gmail.com https://n-capelier.github.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicolas-capelier

# **Technical Game Designer**

Valenciennes (59300) - France Driving license and vehicle Willing to relocate

# **ABOUT ME**

Passionate about online games, programming and game design, I want to use my skills and move towards technical game design. My collaborators describe me as an experienced Unity Engine user and a versatile person willing to help others.

# **SKILLS**

# **Game Development**

- Game Design (system design, balancing)
- Unity Engine (2D & 3D) and C#
- Networking (Fish-Networking, Mirror)
- Technical pipeline (development, balancing, integration)
- Tool design and development
- Versionning (Git, Plastic SCM)
- Documentation (Notion, Mermaid diagrams, Google Suite)
- Management (Notion, Trello, Jira)

# Languages

- French (native)

#### **Interests**

- eSports
- Online multiplayer games

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE & EDUCATION

# Reign of Dwarf, Online gameplay programmer, Internship at AnkleBreaker Studio

June 2023 - October 2023

- Team of 11 game developers
- Development of a 3D multiplayer survival game for PC on UnityEngine
- Development of online features

# Seance, Technical game designer & Lead programmer, Master degree project

October 2022 - June 2023

Valenciennes, France

- Development of a 3D multiplayer game for PC on UnityEngine
- Programming pipeline and project architecture
- Development of online features

# Freelance, Technical game design consultant

- Consulting for Novaa Inc.

December 2022 - March 2023

July 2021 - December 2022

Personnal project

Personnal project

Team of 9 students

## Fiverr gigs, Unity and C# teacher and game prototyping

- Lessons based on constant communication with the student to focus on their needs.
- 2D and 3D game prototypes on UnityEngine
- Game design feedback

# Fall Garden, Lead programmer, School internship

July 2021 - August 2021

Team of 8 students

- Development of a 3D mobile game for Android on UnityEngine
- Programming pipeline and project architecture
- Features and systems development
- Supervisvision of 4 game designers on the programming of the content.

#### Set&Match Compagnon, Backend programmer, Internship at @HomeStudio

July 2020 - August 2020 Team of 2 game developers

- Development of a 2D mobile application for Android and IOS on UnityEngine
- Project architecture
- Networking, geolocation and advertising

# Game Design and Management master degree, RUBIKA Supinfogame

2018 - 2023

Valenciennes, France

Education

- Game Design, Management, UX, Prototyping

- English (fluent)

- Role-playing games

- Modern science